片名:人骨拼圖
"犯罪現場 林肯萊姆著"
"林肯萊姆" "犯罪學專家及作家"
"紐約謀殺案翻案"
"員警在六樁謀殺案現場 因故布疑陣被捕"
Paulie, how's it look?
保利 情況如何?
Snitch says the cop's body's...
線民說員警的屍體...
...about 300 yards down in the abandoned tunnel
...約在離廢棄遂道入口三百碼處
- Howie? - Right behind you, Captain.
- 郝威? - 我在這 隊長
Keep back till I process the scene.
我沒有檢查現場前先不要進來
"紐約警局罪案組"
Watch out below!
下麵小心點
"入境"
So where the hell is the car?
車子到底在哪裡?
I don't know.
我不知道
That's the last time I take a red-eye.
我再也不坐夜間班機了
Maybe we can take a cab.
說不定可以叫計程車
I'm gonna fire this son of a bitch.
我要開除這個渾蛋
He's always got an excuse.
他每次都有藉口
Come on, we'll be home before you know it, hmm?
走吧 我們很快就會到家了
Yeah.
好吧
Excuse me.
對不起
Excuse me, I think you're going the wrong way.
對不起 你好像走錯路了
Honey, honey, wake up.
親愛的 快起來
We're lost, or he's taking us for a ride.
我們若不是迷路了 就是司機故意帶我們繞遠路
We're in the middle of nowhere.
這裡簡直前不著村後不著店
Where the hell you going? I said fifth Avenue.
你要去哪裡? 我不是說要去第五大道嗎
We're not tourists here, man.
我們可不是觀光客
Hey, where are you going?
你要去哪裡?
Let us out. Stop the car.
讓我們下車 快停車
- Stop this car, man! - Stop the car!
- 快停車 夥計 - 快停車
Shit.
該死
- Oh, my God. - Son of a bitch.
- 我的天啊 - 真是渾蛋
Stop the goddamn car!
你他媽的快停車
- Stop it, please. - Stop the car.
- 請你停車 - 停車
Stop this car, goddamn it! Stop this car!
該死的 快停車 快停車
Good morning.
早安
You look a little dehydrated.
你看起來好像有點脫水
How about some juice?
要不要喝點果汁?
How about two fingers of vodka?
給我一杯伏特加好不好?
Isn't it a little early for vodka?
現在喝酒太早了吧?
Time, as you well know, is a relative consideration, Thelma.
你也知道時間是相對的
- Juice. - Vodka.
- 你只能喝果汁 - 我要伏特加
- 喝果汁吧 - 伏特加
Juice
喝果汁
- Coming! - Join me in a drink, Richard?
- 來了! - 一塊兒喝一杯 理查
I'd love to, but a med tech with liquor on his breath, I think not.
我很想喝 不過醉醺醺怎麼上班
Thanks.
我看還是算了
So, how are you?
你好嗎?
I'm better than your heart-pacing gear.
我比你的心跳節律器好多了
Every time I'm here, it's skewed further out of spec. You need a new unit.
它實在是每況愈下 你需要換個新的
I really need a new body.
我需要的是一個新的身體
I'm afraid I can't help you with that.
這我恐怕就愛莫能助了
- I'll bring you a new unit tomorrow. - Okay.
- 我明天幫你換個新的 - 好
- This one'll be stable till then. - Thank you, Richard.
- 這一個暫時還不會壞 - 謝謝你 理查
- Take it easy. - I'll take it any way I can get it.
- 保重 - 我會盡力的
- How's he doing this morning? - He asked for vodka again.
- 他今天早上情況如何? - 他又說要喝伏特加
- Give him any? - No!
- 有沒有給他? - 當然沒有!
- Good morning, Doctor. - Hi, Richard.
- 早安 醫生 - 嗨 理查
Hey, would you look at this! Peregrine falcon. Am I right?
看 是獵鷹 對不對?
Yep. He likes cripples.
對 它最喜歡殘廢了
Yeah, there was a piece about them in the Times the other day...
前幾天 我還在時報雜誌上看到
nesting all over the city.
它們在紐約市中到處築巢
Something to do with architecture of all these old buildings.
顯然它們特別喜歡 這種老式建築物
I thought he liked my company.
我還以為它是喜歡陪我呢
They're a little shy. Don't take it personally, Barry.
它們有點害羞 你別放在心上 貝瑞
- Drink, Doc? - No, thanks, Thelma, I'm fine.
- 要不要喝點東西 醫生? - 不用了 瑟瑪
Bed mode.
調整床墊
- Got vodka in there? - No.
- 有沒有加伏特加? - 沒有
You ain't getting any either.
別妄想喝伏特加
All right, I'll let you guys talk.
你們兩個慢慢聊吧
So, Linc, you can imagine how much sleep
林肯 過去幾天
I've gotten the past few days considering your request.
我因為你提出的要求 而輾轉難眠
That's funny. Since I made my decision, I've been sleeping like a baby.
那倒有趣 我下定決心後 睡得就像嬰兒一樣甜
After all you have survived, beat all the odds...
你排除萬難活了下來...
you know as well as I do, there's work on nerve regeneration every day.
你和我一樣清楚 神經醫學的進步一日千里
One finger, two shoulders and a brain. That's all I have, Barry.
一根手指 兩個肩膀和大腦 我全身上下就剩下這些了
These dysreflexia seizures are occurring more frequently.
我也越來越常抽筋了
Build -up of fluid in my spine is a degenerative condition.
我的脊椎積水 這是一種退化性病況
We both know I'm waiting for the seizure that's gonna make me a vegetable.
我們都知道 我遲早會變成植物人的
I don't wanna be a vegetable, Barry.
我不想變成植物人 貝瑞
I wanna make the final transition on my own terms.
我想自己選擇死亡的時機
I'll get it done with or without you.
不管你幫不幫忙 我都會這麼做
Oh, yeah, I suppose you would.
我想也是
So?
怎麼樣?
- Okay. - Okay what?
- 好 - 好什麼?
Okay, I'll assist you...
好 我會幫你...
in your final transition.
度過你最後一段時光
- What about today? - Linc, preparations have to be made.
- 今天如何? - 林肯 我還要準備呢
This is not a flu shot.
這可不是打傷風疫苗
My business is in order. My bags are packed.
我萬事就緒 只欠東風了
Besides, I've got a medical conference to go to. I've got a plane to catch.
而且我還得去開會呢 我要趕飛機
You're lying.
你騙人
When do you get back?
你什麼時候回來?
Sunday.
禮拜天
Okay. Sunday.
那就星期天吧
- I'll see you then. - Get out before you change your mind.
- 到時候見 - 快走吧 免得你改變心意
Don't bother to get up. I'll show myself out.
別送我了 我自己出去
Yeah, I'll race you to the door.
跟你比 看誰先跑到門口
You are...
你真是個…
a very good friend.
好朋友
Amelia.
愛美莉雅
Hey.
嘿
Hey. Morning.
早安
You okay?
你沒事吧?
Yeah, I'm fine. I just couldn't sleep.
我很好 只是睡不著
- What time is it? - It's early.
- 幾點了? - 還早
I'm gonna be late for work. I gotta shower.
我上班要遲到了 我得去洗個澡
- No, you don't. Stay here. - I gotta go.
- 不行 過來 - 我要走了
Hey, I'll make breakfast?
我做了早餐
No, thanks, I'm gonna be late.
謝了 我要遲到了
Another slam-bam-thank-you-ma'am, huh?
前晚翻雲覆雨 天一亮又要走了?
Look...
聽著...
My therapist tells me...
我的心理醫生告訴我...
I might not be getting what I need out of this relationship.
這段關係也許不能滿足我
What are we doing here? I think we make a great couple.
我們到底在做什麼? 我以為我們是天作之合
You know where I stand on this. You know what I want.
你知道我的立場 你知道我要什麼
Steve, we've been through this.
史提夫 這我們討論過了
I care about you. You know that. I can't make a commitment.
你知道我很關心你 我只是無法做出承諾
Go to work then.
去上班吧
Go ahead. You're gonna be late.
快去 你要遲到了
So, Amelia, is it true you're quitting the cops?
愛美莉雅 聽說你要辭職了?
No, transferring to Youth Services.
不 我要轉到少年隊去
You lucky fuck. You must have one hell of a rabbi downtown.
你真是好狗運 你在總局一定有人罩你
- We're gonna miss you here. - Three-post-eleven here.
- 我們會想念你的 - 這裡是311
- Frightened child at Amtrak site. - I'm a block away. I'll take it.
- 鐵路旁有個小孩 - 離我很近 我去
Some kid found something over at the tracks.
有個小孩似乎在鐵路那裡 發現了什麼
- Finish eating. I'll check it out. - See you, kid.
- 你先吃 我去看看 - 咱們待會兒見
Nothing yet.
還沒有
Wait, I think I see him.
等等 我好像看到他了
Are you the one who called the police?
是你報警的嗎?
Wait there, okay?
別亂跑 知道嗎?
Are you out of your mind?
你瘋啦?
Shut off the engine, all right?
快熄火
There's been a homicide. I can't let you through.
這裡發生兇殺案 我不能讓你通過
- My name is Amelia. What's yours? - Chris.
- 我叫做愛美莉雅 你呢? - 克利斯
Chris, hey. I got a job for you. Here's some money.
克利斯 我要請你幫個忙 這裡有一點錢
I need you to buy me one of those cheapo cardboard cameras the ones you can throw away.
我要請你去幫我買 那種即可丟相機
Okay. Fast as you can.
快去快回
Three-post-eleven to central
311呼叫總部
Get Amtrak to send a bus over here. Get these passengers out of here.
叫鐵路局派部巴士過來 把乘客載走
Captain Cheney, Detective Solomon.
錢尼隊長 我是索羅門警探
- Anything else? - First officer on the scene is there.
- 還有什麼事? - 她是第一個抵達現場的警官
I found strange stuff near the body. I collected it before it was washed away.
我在屍體附近發現了一些證據 趁還沒被沖走之前收了起來
- I also took some pictures. - Thanks.
- 我還照了一些相 - 謝謝
You the one who stopped the train?
攔下火車的人是你?
I thought it would disturb evidence.
我擔心火車會破壞證據
So why not shut down Grand Central while you're at it, hmm, Patrolman Donahue?
為什麼不乾脆連 中央火車站一塊兒封了
Is that right?
你姓唐娜休吧?對不對?
Donaghy.
是唐娜西
A rookie, I take it?
你是菜鳥吧?
No, sir.
不是
Pretty dumb.
你真是笨極了
Captain, guess who the vic turns out to be.
隊長 你猜被害人是誰?
- Talk to me. - Alan fucking Rubin.
- 快說 - 艾倫魯賓
Listen, I don't want anybody in this area except for the crime unit. Okay, Detective
除了重案組之外 這裡閒人勿進 知道了嗎?
Okay?
知道了
Knight to H-6. Check.
騎士到H-6 將軍
You got company. Cops.
有人來找你了 是員警
Tell 'em I'm busy.
告訴他們我很忙
They said it was urgent.
他們說是急事
Tell 'em I'm out running.
告訴他們我去慢跑了
She's too polite for that, Linc.
她太有禮貌說不出口
Hey, looky who's here.
什麼風把你吹來的
I got a serious situation.
我手上有件棘手的案子
It's going around, Paulie.
這件事已經傳開了 保利
Chief Murphy sent me.
是莫菲局長派我來的
The good chief.
原來是局長大人親自下令
Hear about the couple at the airport, got in a taxi yesterday morning?
你有沒有聽說昨天淩晨在機場 上計程車那對夫婦的事?
Never made it home.
他們沒有回到家
We don't watch the news anymore.
他已經不看新聞了
He used to read four papers a day, tape all the news shows.
他以前一天看四份報 還把所有的新聞錄下來
Yeah, and now I just hit the rewind button. A-3.
現在我只按倒帶鈕 A-3
Things never change.
新聞還不都是一個樣子
Yeah, well, that was Alan Rubin and his wife in that taxi.
那對夫婦是艾倫魯賓 和他太太
Found him dead, buried, shot in the face...
他臉部中彈 被人埋在地下
hand sticking out of the ground with his wife's wedding band on his finger...
只有手露在外面 手上還戴著 他太太的結婚戒指
which was skinned to the bone.
那只手指只剩下骨頭
She's still missing.
她仍然下落不明
Excuse me while you catch up, okay?
你們慢慢談吧 我先出去
Don't go too far, Thelma. These nice gentlemen are leaving in 30 seconds.
別跑太遠 瑟瑪 他們30秒後就要走了
Sounds like you got yourself an open-and-shut there, Paulie.
保利 這個案子 聽起來很簡單嘛
I don't think so.
我不這麼想
Yeah? A man won'th millions found dead...
是嗎? 百萬富翁死於非命
with his wife's wedding band on his mutilated hand.
手上又戴著老婆的結婚戒指
What does that tell you?
這代表什麼?
The doer is saying he's got her.
兇手是在告訴你 她在他手上
He's probably contacting the family right now making a ransom demand.
他搞不好現在正在要求贖金
I would 've been paged if he had.
這樣他們早就呼叫我了
Check your batteries. It's definitely a ransom.
你的電池是不是沒電了? 一定會有人要求贖金的
Excuse me, Mr. Rhyme, Kenneth Solomon.
對不起 萊姆先生 我是肯尼索羅門
I've read all your books... Scene of the Crime...
你的書我全看了過 那本犯罪現場
at least a dozen times.
我至少看了十幾遍
It's great to actually meet you.
能夠和你見面是我的榮幸
- Where do you find these guys? - They wanna work with the best.
你是從哪裡找到這些人的?
I guess now you're gonna ask me to discuss the crime scene with you, huh?
他們想和一流好手共事
In fact, we got a bunch of physical evidence...
我想你八成想要和我討論 犯罪現場 對吧?
that doesn't exactly make sense.
事實上 我們手上有許多 看來極不合理的證據
Some seriously weird stuff. It's in the report.
真的很怪異 全寫在報告裡了
You okay?
你沒事吧?
- You okay? - Out! Now!
- 你沒事吧? - 你給我出去
- Anything we can do? - Asses outta here now!
- 我們能幫得上忙嗎? - 快滾
We're gonna get you some air. Come on, breathe for me, Linc.
我們馬上就給你氧氣 快呼吸吧 林肯
I said, out!
我不是叫你們出去嗎?
Come on, deep breaths. Deep breaths, come on.
深呼吸 快點…
Deep breaths. I'm getting a B.P. On you. Come on now, breathe.
深呼吸 我幫你量血壓 快呼吸
Look at me. Breathe.
看著我 呼吸
Look at me. Deep breaths.
看著我 深呼吸
Come on, come on. You've got to take this oxygen.
加油 你一定要吸氧氣
Come on, Rhyme, stay with me.
加油 萊姆 撐下去
Come on, you can do it. Don't go out on me now.
加油 你一定可以的 我不准你死
Come on, look at me.
看著我
You okay?
你還好吧?
I would be okay if your powers of resuscitation were less adept.
如果你沒把我救回來 我會好過得多
Not on my shift, all right.
我當班的時候你不准死
If you have a problem with that, you just fire my ass.
有意見的話僅管開除我
You know I provide generously for you in my will. Keep that in mind.
我的遺囑裡 留了不少錢給你 別忘了
Rhyme, I'm not interested in having this conversation. Okay?
萊姆 我不想談這件事 好嗎?
Okay. Crime scene report Sellitto left...
好 塞裡多留下來的報告
would you load those photos in the viewer for me?
麻煩你把照片放進掃瞄器去
View scan.
啟動掃瞄器
Okay, let's take a look at what we got here.
來看看這到底是怎麼回事
Where it says location... Now, what's that?
屍體在哪裡發現的 那是什麼?
What's it say about that newspaper?
念一下有關報紙的報告
"Newspaper found beneath a coarse-thread hex bolt with 4:00 p.m. Circled on it.'
"報紙被壓在六角型螺絲釘下 四點鐘被圈了起來"
4:00 p.m.
四點鐘
Zoom.
拉近
What about the little piece of paper? What's the number on it?
那張小紙條呢? 上面寫的是什麼數字?
Torn book page with 119 on it.
撕碎的書頁上寫著119
119, 4:00 p.m.
119 下午四點
What's today's date?
今天幾號?
Today's November 9.
今天是11月9日
Phone mode. Sellitto, Paulie. Call.
啟動電話模式 保利塞裡多 撥號
What?
幹嘛?
Sad fact is, a huge percentage of inner-city kids...
令人遺憾的是貧民區的孩子
are having their first drug experiences at the fifth grade level
大多數在五年級就開始吸毒了
Now, here are some of the drugs they'll most likely be offered.
這些是他們最可能吸食的毒品
"麻醉藥及危險藥品"
Marijuana.
大麻
Wouldrt you like to get your hands on that briefcase?
真想拿到那個公事包
Barbiturates, amphetamines.
巴比妥酸鹽 安非他命
Cocaine.
可卡因
Rock cocaine.
結晶可卡因
What is this about?
到底什麼事?
Do you know who Lincoln Rhyme is?
你知道林肯萊姆是誰嗎?
- Textbook guy? - Yeah.
- 那個寫書的人? - 沒錯
What does that have to do with me?
那和我有什麼關係?
You'll find out.
你等著瞧吧
Come in. They're right in there.
請進 他們在裡面
A patrol cop took these pictures?
這些照片是一名巡警拍的?
Yeah, first one on the scene. It started to rain.
沒錯 他是第一個到現場的 當時正開始下雨
Smart guy.
真聰明
Also had the balls to stop an Amtrak from running over the crime scene.
而且還很有種 才敢攔下火車 不讓火車破壞現場
Here she is now. Officer Donahoe...
她來了 唐娜荷警官
meet Lincoln Rhyme.
這位是林肯萊姆
Donaghy.
我姓唐娜西
You took some terrific photographs, Officer.
警官 你照的照片很不錯
You know who I am?
你知道我是誰嗎?
I read your manual at the academy.
我在警校就拜讀過你的大作
What'd you think of it?
有什麼感想?
I'm not a book critic, sir.
我不是書評家
But you found it useful.
你覺得很有用嗎?
Yeah, I guess so.
大概吧
Guess so? Sure, you did. You stopped that train.
大概?才怪 你把火車攔了下來
Photos you took.
你照了照片
I'd say you have a natural instinct for forensics.
我覺得你對辦案很有天份
So what do we got, Paulie?
我們有什麼線索 保利?
We have footprints, size ten, thanks to Officer Donaghy...
有腳印 兇手穿十號鞋 這都得感謝唐娜西警官
using a dollar bill to establish scale.
她想到用一塊錢紙鈔來做比對
We have asbestos on the track bed where there shouldn't be any...
鐵軌上有石棉 這種東西不該出現在這裡
and an iron bolt holding down a piece of paper...
還有被螺絲釘壓住的紙片
with a book page with 119 written on it.
這是一張上面寫著 119被撕碎的書頁
Decaying oxidation on the bolt 's head, but not on the thread...
螺絲頭已經開始氧化了 但螺身還沒有
which says to me that someone removed it from somewhere else...
所以我知道有人 一定是把它從別處拿來
and placed it there recently.
最近才放置在現場
Wouldrt you agree, Officer?
你同意嗎 警官?
Paulie, I'm convinced that this crime scene was staged.
保利 我認為犯罪現場 是兇手設計安排的
- Perp's trying to tell us something. - What the fuck you saying?
- 兇手似乎想告訴我們什麼 - 你在說什麼?
Book page 119. 11/9... That's today date.
書頁上寫著119 那是今天的日期
- Newspaper, 4:00 p.m. What time is it? - 12:15.
- 報上圈著四點 現在幾點? - 12點15分
She's alive.
她還活著
- And he's gonna kill her at 4:00. - P.m.
- 他打算四點殺了她 - 下午四點
We have your interest yet, Officer?
警官 你現在有興趣了嗎?
I want you to work the case with us.
我要你和我們合作偵辦
It's not my area.
這已超出了我的專長
Are you being modest...
你是謙虛...
or are you a little uneasy about doing some real police work?
還是不敢擔起 人民保母的重任?
Excuse me?
你說什麼?
What department you work in, Officer?
你是哪個部門的?
Youth Services Division. I picked her up at orientation.
少年隊 她一來我就選她了
I see, youth services.
我懂了 少年隊
I waited over a year to get that transfer. I'm not gonna jeopardize...
我等了一年才等到這次 調職機會 我不會危及…
Jeopardize what? Cushy desk job?
危及你坐辦公桌的機會嗎?
Forensics is not my area.
法醫學不是我的專長
I disagree with you.
這我不同意
You can't force me to take this assignment.
你不能強迫我接受這個任務
I can.
我可以
And if I refuse?
萬一我拒絕呢?
You'd put your career at risk.
你的事業就岌岌可危
You think, because of your condition, you can push people around?
你以為自己生病 就可以對人頤指氣使嗎?
I'm sorry. That is truly pathetic.
很抱歉 這真的太可悲了
Truly?
真的?
Yeah, damn right.
一點都沒錯
Well, forgive me, truly...
那我真的很抱歉了
if I insist on having someone with your brains and a fresh pair of eyes.
我還是堅持要像你這麼 聰明又見解的人來幫忙
There's a life at stake here, Officer.
我們現在討論可是一條人命呢
We're gonna need some key people and tech support.
幫我找幾名能幹的手下 和技術支援
- I know the guy. - Okay.
- 交給我 - 好
What the hell are you smiling at?
你在笑什麼?
Pull up a chair. Tell me everything you know about the crime scene.
拉把椅子過來 詳細的描述一下犯罪現場
- You saw my report. - I read your report.
- 你看過我的報告 - 我看過了
I wanna know what you felt.
我要知道你的感覺
What you feel...
我要知道你心底深處的感覺
in the deepest recesses of your senses.
你很喜歡聽自己說話 對吧?
You are in love with the sound of your own voice, aren't you?
我想聽的是你的聲音 拉把椅子坐吧 我不會咬你
It's your voice I yearn to hear. Pull up a chair. I won't bite you.
"奪命計程車 艾倫魯賓命喪黃泉"
The rifling on the.38 slug they dug out of the victim...
被害者身上挖出來的 點38子彈
is consistent with a Webley, a very old, turn-of-the-century handgun.
證實是古老的 韋伯利手槍的子彈
Thank you, Kenny. On the big board, please.
謝了 肯尼 把它寫在黑板上
What do you got on that bolt?
螺絲釘查的如何?
Three initials on the head: N.S.G.
頭上刻著N.S.G
And the bolt 's not steel it's iron.
而且不是鋼制的 是鐵制的
Iron? Iron.
鐵?鐵…
Making it old... like the Webley.
所以年代和那把手槍一樣老
Officer Donaghy, what do you know about asbestos?
唐娜西警官 你對石棉知道多少?
It kills hard-working Americans daily.
它是美國工人的頭號殺手
Very good.
很好
- You computer literate? - A little.
- 你會用電腦吧? - 會一點
Where's my Thelma?
瑟瑪 我的瑟瑪呢?
Guess.
你說呢
Thelma, meet Amelia. Amelia, Thelma.
瑟瑪 這位是愛美莉雅 愛美莉雅 這位是瑟瑪
Amelia hates my books and computers, but she's got an A-plus nose for evidence...
愛美莉雅討厭我的書和電腦 可是她搜集證據的功夫一流
so I want you to give her a crash course in how to access D.E.P. Files.
麻煩你教教她 如何取得DEP檔案
Check if there's any large asbestos cleanups going on in the city.
查查看紐約有沒有什麼地方 正在清石棉
A.S.A.P.
快點去辦
- Where the hell is Eddie Ortiz? - I'm right here!
- 艾迪歐提茲在哪裡? - 我在這裡
How's the world 's crankiest criminalist doing?
我們這位脾氣古怪的 犯罪學家還好嗎?
Playing beat the clock.
我在和時間賽跑
Everybody's worst nightmare.
這簡直是大家的惡夢
You get into a cab, and there's a psycho from Jersey driving.
一不小心就坐上了 澤西狂人開的計程車
We don't know he's from Jersey.
我們不知道兇手是澤西來的
Yeah, Bayonne. It's the toxins in the water over there.
他們在貝玉恩的海裡 找到一輛計程車
- What'd you do, bring the whole lab? - Mama always said be prepared.
- 你把實驗室都搬來啦? - 我媽叫我隨時準備充份
- Where do you want this? - Just put it in the corner.
- 你要把這個放在哪裡? - 放在角落裡
How is your mother?
你媽還好嗎?
She's 76, and she's schtupping some guy named Morris. Can you believe it?
她76歲了 居然還和一個 叫做莫利斯的男人搞七撚三
- God bless her. - It's Morris I'm worried about.
- 願上帝保佑她 - 我擔心的是莫利斯
He's 79, with a tricky ticker and an active pecker.
他79了 心臟不行 那話兒還勇的很
Afternoon. Captain Cheney.
午安 我是錢尼隊長
What's your address?
地址查的如何?
There's about a dozen cleanups scattered across the five boroughs.
紐約市有十幾個石棉廠
Put it up on the viewer for me, will you, please?
麻煩你把地址放進掃瞄器
Narrow it down to the oldest location as soon as you can.
找出其中最古老的一處
- How you doing, Howard? - Fine, thank you.
- 霍華 你好嗎? - 很好 謝謝你
- How's it going? - Middle of the middle, as you can see.
- 情況如何? - 還是一團亂 沒有頭緒
Hey, Linc, look what I found on the threading of that iron bolt.
林肯 看看我在螺絲釘 的螺線上找到什麼
Look, I was hoping to grab a minute with you.
你不介意的話 我想和你談談
- If you don't mind. - Excuse me, Howard.
對不起 霍華
Sorry.
對不起
We got Officer Donaghy to thank here for photographing the crucial evidence.
多虧唐娜西警官 拍下重要證據的照片
Crucial evidence? We don't know that.
重要證據? 現在這麼說言之過早
I just stopped by to make sure you had all the support you need.
我只是過來看看 你需要的東西是不是都齊了
I'm putting the full resources of my department here at your disposal
本單位全力支援你
And I appreciate it, Howie, thank you.
感激不盡 霍華
But the thing is, Linc...
不過問題是…
I've formalized department standard procedure since you were in charge...
本案既然由你負責 我又正式 宣佈了我們辦案的程式…
Eddie, could you put what you got up on my screen, please?
艾迪 麻煩你把你的結果 放在我的螢幕上
So I'd appreciate it if you kept me in the loop.
我希望你能夠隨時 向我報告進度
Absolutely.
沒問題
At all times.
隨時向我報告
At all... Eddie, what the hell is that we're looking at?
隨時… 艾迪 這到底是什麼玩意兒?
Old paper.
這張紙很舊了
Coarse grade.
紙質很粗糙
I say, 80, 90 years old.
大概有8 90年了
Turn of the century, it looks like.
應該是本世紀初的紙吧
This perp likes old.
這個兇手偏愛老的東西
- I'll be in my office if you need me. - Yeah, okay.
- 我在辦公室 有事找我 - 知道了
Good.
好
Old paper.
陳年老紙
Old gun.
舊手槍
Buried his victim in a vintage Civil War railroad bed.
把被害人埋在內戰時期的 鐵軌底座附近
Sand.
沙…
Eddie, what do you got on the sand?
你對沙的分析結果如何?
Doesrt really look like sand.
不像沙
I'm not sure.
我不確定
Can you individuate it?
你能不能分化檢驗一下?
- If I had E.D.X., I could do anything. - We don't have that, Eddie.
- 如果有EDX的話就好了 - 我們沒有那玩意兒
Look who forgot their chill pill this morning. Excuse me.
有人今天早上 忘了吃鎮定丸哦!
Come on, I'm all over this thing now.
別煩我了 我正在忙
We're talking pearly looking.
看起來有點像珍珠
Some kind of shellfish or something.
應該是貝殼的一種吧
Oysters shells, maybe?
是不是牡蠣殼?
Could be.
有可能
Definitely. If I had to bet on it, I'd say it was. Sure.
我認為八成是牡蠣殼
I got it. The oldest asbestos sites are coming up now.
我查到最古老的石棉廠了
"鐵 NSG 古老石棉 沙 報紙 1913"
In 1913, when the Woolwon'th Building was being built...
1913年 吳華茲大樓動工興建時
workmen found the body of this rich industrialist, Talbot Soames.
工人找到富有企業家 塔伯索瑪的遺骸
He'd been kidnapped the year before, shot in the head and buried...
他在一年前被綁架 頭部中彈而死
in what they thought was white sand but turned out to be oyster shells.
並且被埋在白色的 牡蠣殼碎屑中
Crushed oyster shells... That's what they used as landfill in lower Manattan.
下曼哈頓的填地土中 用了許多壓碎的牡蠣殼
That's how Pearl Street got its name. That's where Ms. Rubin is gonna be...
珍珠街就是因此而得名 魯賓太太就在那裡
somewhere downtown.
就在市中心某處
She's gonna be underground.
她一定在地下
She's gonna be in a basement...
一定是被關在地下室中
near or in the Woolwon'th Building.
而且一定是在吳華茲大廈附近
Paulie, call Emergency Services Unit to meet us at the Woolwon'th Building.
保利 通知緊急辦案小組 在吳華茲大廈和我們會合
Tell them to start their search. Maybe we'll get lucky.
叫他們開始搜 說不定這次我們會走運
Okay? Eddie, did you bring your van?
艾迪 你有開箱形車來嗎?
- It's downstairs. - We're gonna need it.
- 就停在樓下 - 我們會用到你的車
Throw your keys to Amelia. Paulie, you and Solomon go with her.
把鑰匙交給愛美莉雅 保利 你和索羅門陪她去
- Shouldrt I go too? - You stay. We're gonna work that bolt.
- 我不該跟他們去嗎? - 你留下 繼續研究螺絲
- That's the missing piece. - Should we keep Cheney in the loop?
- 這是唯一沒有明朗的關鍵 - 我們不該通知錢尼嗎?
Fuck him.
去他的
Just trust me.
愛美莉雅 相信我
Just follow those instincts you were born with. I'll be with you...
運用你天生的本能
every step of the way.
我會從頭到尾陪著你
Jesus, 25 minutes left.
天啊 只剩下25分鐘了
How did Rhyme get to be that way?
萊姆怎麼會這樣?
He was born brilliant. It happens.
有些人就是天生聰明
I mean the physical part.
我是說他為什麼會癱瘓?
About four years ago, he was working the body of a transit cop...
四年前他在調查 一名被人發現…
found shot in a subway tunnel
死在地鐵遂道中警員的屍體
Beam came down and damn near cut him in half.
遂道的橫樑倒了下來 差點把他壓成兩半
Jesus.
天啊
- Family? - Married sister in Phoenix.
- 他有沒有家人? - 他妹妹已婚 住在鳳凰城
He never sees her. Cut himself off.
他不願見她 把自己封閉起來
Technically, he's still active duty collecting full pay.
技術上而言 他仍然當差 領全薪
P.B.A. Insurance picks up round-the-clock care and the gadgets.
保險公司支付全天看護 和醫療儀器的費用
On weekends, always one or two cops there, lending a hand.
我們同仁週末會去幫他忙
- Tough deal winding up like that. - You won't hear him complain about it.
- 這種下場真慘 - 他從不抱怨
He gets too much pleasure pushing other people 's buttons.
他太享受這種頤指氣使的滋味
In your case, I'd be complimented.
這對你而言 是一種讚美
You gotta learn to relax around a compliment...
你在接受讚美時 不該還這麼死板
especially one from Rhyme.
特別當讚美你的人是萊姆時
- You can be a little grating. - Me?
- 你有時太緊張了 - 我嗎?
Kiddo, if you were any more wound up, you'd be a Timex.
你再緊張點就會崩潰的
He was a human dynamo. Writing books, lecturing all over the world...
他以前活力十足 寫書、到全球講學
giving expert opinion in trials...
出庭時以專家身份作證
working half the crimes scenes in the city.
本市有半數以上的罪案現場 都交由他調查
- You know what he did on his downtime? - I can't imagine.
- 你猜他閑蝦時做什麼? - 我猜不出
He'd collect things... dirt, metals, plastics...
他四處搜集東西 土壞、金屬片、塑膠…
hubcaps, plants, musical strings...
輪胎蓋、琴弦…
medical tools... anything you could think of.
醫療工具 簡直是包羅萬象
Obsessive.
真是走火入魔
He'd have it all analyzed and catalogued for his database.
他分析這些東西後 全部歸入資料庫
Jesus Christ! I'd like to get there in one piece, if possible.
拜託你 小姐 我不想英年早逝
"N.S.G"
Yeah, find out about that. That might be good. What else?
你去查查 也許有用 還有什麼?
Nicholas Steven Gerard, elevator construction.
尼可拉斯史帝芬傑拉德 電梯工程公司
- Gotta be underground. - I got a subway builder here.
- 一定要在地下才行 - 有一家地鐵工程公司
- Subway builder's out. - N.S. G... Niagara Steam Generation.
- 別管地鐵工程公司 - NSG尼加拉蒸氣機公司
Bought by Eastern Gas and Electric in 1928.
1928年時 被東方瓦斯電力公司收購
The six-inch iron bolt was used mainly for steam pipe assemblies.
這種六英寸鐵制螺絲釘 主要用在組合蒸氣管上
Forty-five, you got 11 minutes left. Where the hell are you?
49號 你們只剩下11分 你們到底在哪裡?
We just hit the financial district.
我們剛到金融區
There's a steam junction with big asbestos-coated pipes.
附近應該有蒸氣管交接處 應該有很多覆蓋著石棉的管線
That's where our victim's gonna be. I bet my legs on it...
我們的被害人就會在那裡...
Wall and Nassau.
她會在華爾和拿索街口
Has E.S.U. Been notified?
有沒有通知緊急辦案小組?
Yeah, they're on their way.
有 他們也快到了
E.S.U. Says that steam is released through that junction every day at 4:00.
緊急小組說 那裡每天四點會放蒸氣
Shit, what's this asshole up to?
該死 這渾球到底要做什麼?
I don't know, but it's gonna happen in about ten minutes and 30 seconds.
我不知道 但你們只剩下 10分30秒了
All right, Linc, we're here. We're going down there.
好 林肯 我們到了 我們現在就要下去
Yeah, I'm here.
我在
It's their job to try and save Mrs. Rubirs life.
他們的工作是去救魯賓太太
It's your job to get ready and work the crime scene if necessary.
而你的工作則是準備好 必要時去檢查犯罪現場
There's some things you're gonna need, so look in the back of the truck.
你會需要一些東西 看看車子後面
You'll see an aluminum suitcase and a radio headset.
應該有一個鋁制的手提箱 和無線電耳機
- See it? - Yeah, I see them.
- 看到了嗎? - 我看到了
There must be a way in.
一定有辦法可以進去
- What's the problem here? - Fucking valves freeze up easy.
- 怎麼回事? - 活門一下子就被凍住了
Come on, guys, shut it off.
各位快把它關掉
- You there? - I'm here.
- 你還在嗎? - 還在
- I'm inside the pipe. - One, two, three.
- 我現在已經爬到管子裡去了 - 1 2 3
Go!
用力!
I think I hear something. I hear something.
我好像聽到什麼了 我聽到聲音了
What is it? Someone's in there! I can hear her crying.
怎麼了?有人在裡面 我能聽到她的哭聲
Everyone, quiet now.
大家安靜
Mrs. Rubin?
魯賓太太?
She's in there. Mrs. Rubin!
她在裡面 魯賓太太!
We're on our way in now. Come on, guys.
我們現在就要進去了 各位快點
Let's go. Let's hurry the fuck up!
我們動作要快一點
- Jesus Christ. - Get a drill and a tap.
- 天啊 - 去找個電鑽和插頭來
Somebody cut this thing halfway through.
這玩意已經 先被人切斷一半了
Let's dig!
我們快挖!
Move back!
退後!
Linc, she's gone.
林肯 她死了
The whole place is scalded in steam.
整個地方被蒸氣燙得火熱
Let's go. Move away.
大家快讓開
Nothing to see here.
這裡沒什麼好看的
E.S.U. Are gonna blow a hole in the subbasement wall. No other way in.
緊急小組要炸開地下第二層 只有這樣才能進去
I am working with Chief Murphy's authorization on this, right?
莫菲局長已經 充份授權給我了 對吧?
Yeah, that's right.
沒錯
I don't want E.S.U. Guys rushing in there,
我不要緊急小組 冒然沖進去 破壞現場
trampling the evidence before we get a chance to run the scene.
我們要先勘查過現場
What do you want?
你要怎麼做?
I want Donaghy to go in first.
我要唐娜西先進去
Come on, Linc, she's not trained for this.
別這樣 林肯 她沒有受過這種訓練
We can get our asses in a sling.
她訓練不夠 一搞砸 我們麻煩就大了
My ass has been in a sling for four years.
我這四年來麻煩一直很大
Tell Hanson and his beasts that's what I want. Period.
告訴韓森和他的手下 這是我的意思
All right, you got it.
沒問題
Okay, let's move!
大家快上!
I'm doing this under protest.
我抗議你們這種作法
The perp could still be in there.
兇手搞不好還在裡面
Rhyme's in charge, and they're his orders.
這是萊姆的命令 這裡由他當家
You can't handle it in there, I want you to get your ass out.
如果你無法處理 就快點出來
- Amelia, you ready? - Yeah.
- 愛美莉雅 準備好了嗎? - 好了
You listen to me.
你聽好了
I'm with you every step of the way.
我會從頭到尾陪著你
Go on.
去吧
Good luck.
祝你好運
- I'm in. - Tell me what you see.
- 我進來了 - 告訴我你看到什麼了
Everything's been boiled to hell.
這裡所有的東西都燙焦了
Oh, God.
天啊
What is it?
什麼事?
It's an awful smell.
味道好刺鼻
That means you're close.
這表示你接近了
- I can't believe I'm doing this. - You're fine.
- 我真不敢相信我這麼做 - 你沒事的
Just fine. You're doing great. Just remember the academy.
你沒事 你做的很好 別忘了警校學到的事
When you walk, move in a straight line.
你要以直線前進
We don't want to disturb any footprints he might've left.
不要弄亂了他 可能留下來的足印
Yes, assuming he's gone.
是啊 假設他已經走了!
There's no footprints. There's nothing yet.
我沒有看到腳印 什麼都還沒看到
Oh, God.
天啊
What?
什麼事?
Talk to me.
快告訴我
I can see her.
我看到她了
The steam pipe was opened, and she's tied down right in front of it.
蒸氣管被打開了 她被綁在蒸氣管前
Okay. There's nothing you can do about that now.
你現在也無能為力
Can't do anything but help her by working the crime scene.
你除了檢查犯罪現場外 什麼都不能做
That's your job.
那是你的工作
Open your suitcase, get your camera.
打開打提箱 把相機拿出來
I can't do this.
我做不來
You can do it. Yes, you can. Yesterday you stopped a train.
你行的 昨天你還攔下了一列火車
You can do anything you want when you put your mind to it.
天下無難事 只怕有心人
Don't work me, Rhyme.
別逼我 萊姆
Just tell me what to do next.
我接下來要做什麼?
Very slowly, walk the grid...
慢慢的走過框架…
one foot in front of the other.
一步一步前進
I want you to look around you now. Remember...
我要你看看四周 記得…
crime scenes are three-dimensional...floors, walls and ceilings.
犯罪現場是個立體空間 有地板 牆壁和天花板
Yeah, I'm here.
我在聽
There's something strange.
有一件事很不尋常
Things he left for us?
他有留下東西給我們?
Yes.
是的
- In a cluster again? - There's a small piece of wood...
- 又是一團? - 有一小塊木頭
and it looks like some hair.
還有一些像毛髮的東西
I'm gonna walk you through collecting the evidence.
我要教你怎麼收集證據
You do everything exactly as I say.
你照著我的話去做
- Oh, Jesus. - Talk to me.
- 我的天啊 - 告訴我什麼事
- It's a bloody bone. - Where is it?
- 是一根帶血的骨頭 - 在哪裡?
It's in my fucking hand.
就在我手上
Human?
人骨嗎?
I think so, yeah.
應該是的 沒錯
Photograph it...
先拍照…
bag it.
再裝袋
Okay, that's it. I'm outta here.
夠了 我要離開這裡
One more thing.
還有一件事
We gotta process the body.
我們要檢查屍體
What? I'm no medical examiner. I can't do that.
什麼?我不是法醫 我做不來
I'm not asking you to do an autopsy.
我不是要你解剖屍體
I just want you to... just describe the restraints.
我要你告訴我 她是怎麼被綁的
They're strange-looking handcuffs.
她被奇怪的手銬銬住
They look more like old shackles or something.
看起來是一種很老的手銬
And there's a chain across her waist.
她手腕上 繞著一條鐵鍊
And her feet are...
她的腿…
bound with a rope.
被繩子綁住了
Hands above her head?
雙手銬在頭上?
Yeah.
是的
There's also a large piece of flesh missing from her right forearm.
她右上臂少了一塊肉
It's right down to the bone, like it was surgically removed.
傷口深可見骨 看起來似乎是以外科手法切除
This is what I want you to do.
以下是我要你做的事
We're gonna need those handcuffs.
我們需要這副手銬
It's probably our best chance for good prints.
這是你採集指紋的 最好機會
The M.E. Can remove them when they get here.
讓辦案小組來拿手銬
The M.E. Is all thumbs. They'll mess up the prints.
辦案小組都是粗手粗腳的人 他們會弄亂指紋的
Look in the suitcase. There's a small saw.
手提箱裡應該有一把小鋸子
Okay.
找到了
I want you to saw her hands off at the wrist line.
把她的手從手腕處鋸掉
We gotta have those cuffs for prints.
我們需要取得手銬 以採集指紋
I can't.
我做不到
Cut her hands off. We need the handcuffs.
把她的手鋸掉 我們需要那副手銬
I can't. No.
我做不到 不行
Saw off her hands, take off the cuffs.
鋸掉她的手 拿下手銬
Listen to me. Saw off her h... We need those cuffs.
聽我說 鋸掉她的… 我們需要那副手銬
I can't!
我不能!
- Amelia, we need... - No, fuck you!
- 愛美莉雅 我們需要… - 不 去你的!
If he wants that womars hands cut off, he can come down and do it himself.
他想要鋸掉那個女人的手 就自己動手
"紐約市警局人事資料 愛美莉雅唐娜西"
"父親 紐約市員警 自殺身亡"
"屍體由女兒愛美莉雅發現 她也是紐約市員警"
Hello?
哈囉?
Who is it?
哪位?
Jesus.
天啊
- Take it easy. - Shit, what are you doing?
別緊張
- You okay? - Am I okay? What are you doing?
- 你沒事吧? - 你到底在幹嘛?
Rhyme has been trying to call you for hours.
萊姆打電話打了一個小時
Your phone's down. He was concerned.
你的電話不通 他很擔心
My phone's fine. I don't need his concern.
我的電話沒問題 我不需要他關心
He needs you over at his place right away.
他要你馬上到他那兒去
I don't work for Lincoln Rhyme.
我不為林肯萊姆工作
Rhyme thinks the evidence you collected indicates there's another vic in play.
萊姆認為你收集到的證據表示 兇手手上還有一名被害人
And he's laying that at my feet?
給這個消息 他就想使我再去替他做事?
Don't shoot the messenger.
兩國相爭不斬來使
- You just move in? - Yeah, about a year ago.
- 你剛搬來? - 一年前才搬來的
Really?
真的嗎?
"我和爸爸"
You were a model.
你以前是模特兒
Yeah, when I was a kid.
小時候是
Kid model to street cop... there's a leap.
少女模特兒變成員警 真是一大轉變
For whatever it's won'th...
我說這話也許沒什麼幫助…
I thought what you did today was pretty damn terrific.
我認為你今天的表現十分出色
Hey, you guys. I'm outta here.
各位 我要走了
I'm gonna grab a cab. I got a paper to finish.
我要叫部計程車回去趕報告
- I'm just gonna hang. - I'll be there in a minute.
- 我還要再留一會兒 - 我待會兒就來
Taxi!
計程車!
That bone's definitely not human.
那根骨頭絕對不是人骨
- And the hair? - Not human either.
- 那毛髮呢? - 也不是人類的
- Well, what is it? - Working fast as I can.
- 那到底是什麼動物的? - 我正在查
Glad to see you could join us.
很高興看到你重新歸隊
I got Cheney on the line. He wants you to brief him.
錢尼打電話來要你向他報告
Tell him I'll call him back.
告訴他我會回電
Two things:
我有兩件事要說:
First, you did a hell of a job locating the evidence.
第一 你今天收集證據 做的很不錯
There's no question the perp knows forensics.
顯然兇手對警方辦案手法 十分熟悉
Now, as for the other thing...
至於另外一件事嘛…
you know, the victim's hands... well, maybe...
叫你鋸掉被害人的手 也許…
maybe it was too much to handle, so we'll just forget it.
也許稍嫌過份了 我們就忘了這回事吧
Is that your version of an apology?
你這算是在道歉嗎?
An apology? Is that why you came over here?
道歉? 你是為了這個而來的嗎?
- You really are a piece of work. - Well, aren't we a pair?
- 你真不簡單 - 你也一樣
I think you're terrific.
我覺得你很棒
You got a hell of an arrest record too.
你的辦案成績十分出色
High marks from all your bosses, definite gold shield potential
所有上司都對你讚不絕口 你未來大有可為
Why you want to throw it all away to chase youth offenders?
你難道要放棄這一切 去追小太保嗎?
Oh, I don't feel I have any need to explain that to you.
我不需要對你解釋
Come on, Amelia. Cop to cop.
愛美莉雅 咱們有話直說
Cop to cop, let's just leave it at " personal reasons.'
就算是為了"私人理由"吧
Okay.
好
Doesrt have anything to do with your father, does it?
這和你父親沒關係吧?
"父親 紐約市警局 自殺身亡"
Man, you just keep charging at walls, don't you?
你還真是窮追不捨
Stubbornness is something we both share.
我們兩個都一樣頑固
They say we come into this world with a genetically preordained destiny.
有人說人一出生命運就註定了
I don't believe it.
但我不相信
For example, neither of my parents had more than an eighth grade education.
比如說我父母 都沒有受過高等教育
Never read more than one book between them... not one.
兩個人念的書加起來不到一本
I've read thousands.
我卻盡覽群書
- I've written a dozen. - What's your point?
- 我還寫了十幾本 - 你這話有什麼重點?
My point is that destiny is what you make it.
重點是命運是靠自己開創的
Whatever happened to your father doesn't mean it's gonna happen to you.
你不見得會有 和你父親一樣的下場
You're a great cop. You'd make a terrific detective.
你是個好員警 而且會成為一個好警探
It's a gift.
這是你的天賦
Don't throw it away.
別白白浪費了
Report from the taxi commission.
計程車工會來了一份報告
An NYU student was abducted late last night.
昨晚有個紐約大學的學生 被綁架了
His girlfriend saw him struggling to get out...
他的女朋友看到他掙扎想下車
as the taxi driver was bludgeoning him with a flashlight.
計程車司機卻拿手電筒打他
No description of the driver.
她無法描述司機的長相
Okay, everybody. This could be our next victim.
各位 這可能是下一位受害者
Yeah, Tony. Paulie here. It looks like we got another victim.
東尼 我是保利 似乎又有新受害者了
Did you get a deadline off that evidence yet?
證據上面有沒有標明時限?
Not yet. Something I was hoping you'd help me with.
還沒有 我希望你能幫我查明這點
Anyone for some osso buco?
有人想要吃燉小牛肉嗎?
What?
什麼?
The bone we found at the Wall Street scene...
我們在華爾街犯罪現場 找到的骨頭
veal shank...
是小牛的脛骨
braised and overly salted to boot.
是被極端熟練的手法處理過的
- Cow bone? - Uh-huh.
- 牛骨? - 是的
And I also found a piece of that old paper...
我同時也在骨頭裡面
imbedded in the bone.
找到一小片很舊的紙 來看看吧
What's going on here?
這裡是怎麼回事?
Just do what you need to do as quickly as possible, okay, Richard?
你速戰速決快點離開這裡 知道嗎 理查?
It's about the hair follicles. He says they're not human.
毛髮的報告出來了 他說不是人類的毛髮
A rodent, probably a rat.
也許是老鼠的
And get this: They were shaved off.
而且還是被剃下來的呢
Oh, now we're looking for a rat that shaves.
難不成兇手是只 會刮鬍子的老鼠?
- I really like that. - I've known a few in my time.
- 很不錯 - 我以前認識幾隻這樣的鼠輩
- How 'bout you, Amelia? - More than a few.
- 你呢 愛美莉雅? - 我認識的鼠輩多著呢
It's consistent with underground, that's for sure.
這和"地下"相符合
What's he trying to say to us?
他想說什麼?
Definitely communicating in our language...
他對警方十分熟悉
leaving clues... forensic clues at that.
到處留下蛛絲馬跡 而且還是犯罪學上的證據
Maybe it's a cop.
也許是個員警
Maybe.
也許
Maybe he's trying to share the responsibility of these murders with us.
也許他想讓我們共同承擔 這些謀殺案的罪惡
If we don't figure out the clues in time, the blood's on our hands.
如果我們不及時破解證據 就如同害死被害人
We don't find the victim in time, we're as responsible for the murders as he is.
如果不及時找到被害人 我們就和他一樣有罪
What you got on the dirt you scraped from the wood, Eddie?
艾迪 從木頭上刮下的 土壞分析結果如何?
I don't have it 100% individuated, but it does appear nitrogen-rich.
還沒有完全出來 不過看來含氮量頗高
- All set, ready to rock and roll. - All right.
- 可以用了 - 很好
- Thanks for rushing. I appreciate it. - All right, Thelma.
- 謝謝你這麼速戰速決 - 別客氣 瑟瑪
Thank you, Richard.
謝謝你 理查
Nitrogen rich, explosive carbons... where do you find those in New York?
含氮量豐富 易爆碳… 紐約哪裡有這些東西?
Bomb sites, shooting ranges.
試爆場 射擊練習場
Maybe an old fort or an armory?
會不會是舊碉堡或兵工廠?
Let's not forget the shit factor, guys.
別忘了糞便
The what?
什麼?
Manure becomes a nitrate when it's aged.
堆肥放久了也會變成硝酸鹽
That's true.
真的嗎?
And you got cow bones, huh?
我們還找到牛骨 對吧?
Old cow bones, old manure. Turn of the century, cows, farms...
陳年牛骨和陳年堆肥 本世紀初 牛、農場…
pastures, rats...
草原、老鼠…
Dead cows.
死牛
Where do you find... In stockyards.
在哪裡能找到… 臨時牲畜圍欄
Slaughterhouses, that's what we want to look for.
屠宰場 我們要找屠宰場
Stockyards and slaughterhouses from the turn of the century.
本世紀初的臨時畜欄和屠宰場
- Let's start there. - Check the internet.
- 我們從那裡著手 - 上網去查一下
Okay, I want tax records, sanitation records and building code inspections...
我要繳稅記錄、衛生查驗記錄 和建築局檢查結果
last hundred years, okay?
過去一百年的全要 知道嗎?
"1號 艾倫魯賓 2號 琳西魯賓"
Man, your blood pressure is way up.
你的血壓好高啊
- You're pushing it too hard, Rhyme. - I understand, Thelma.
- 你太勞累了 萊姆 - 我知道 瑟瑪
What do we got on the stockyards over there?
臨時畜欄查的如何?
- We're almost there. - Okay, that one's no good.
- 快有結果了 - 那不行
- You okay? - No, I'm not okay.
- 你還好吧? - 不 我不好
Can't figure out this damn time line or these shards of cardboard.
我想不出時限 也想不出這些紙的含意
I don't know what the hell it means.
我搞不清楚它們的意義
We got three defunct stockyards sites.
我找到三個廢棄的畜欄
There's one on the east side, Lexington and the Harlem River viaduct.
有一個在東邊位於雷辛頓 和哈林河畔的高架橋下
Solomon, put the box down, and mark them on the viewer as she calls them out.
索羅門 把箱子放下來 把她說的地址圈出來
Your blood pressure's gonna blow a gasket if you don't slow down.
你再這樣下去 血壓會過高
My body has a mind of its own. It doesn't listen to me.
我的身體自有主張 它根本不聽我的
All right?
知道嗎?
What else, Amelia?
還有呢 愛美莉雅?
Yeah, there's another on the Hudson up at 155th.
另外一個位於 哈德遜及155街口
Mark it down, Solomon.
標出來 索羅門
Look, your stats are going down. You saw him have a seizure the other day.
你情況不好 你們前幾天 也看過他發作的情況
What else?
還有呢?
There's one underground at Greenwich and Houston.
還有一座位於格林威治 和豪斯頓的地下
- Mark it down, Solomon. - Why don't you knock it off, Lincoln?
- 標出來 索羅門 - 你為什麼不休息一下 林肯
I don't need to knock it off!
我不用休息
What was the first one that you mentioned?
你說的第一座在哪裡?
Lexington and the Harlem River viaduct.
雷辛頓和哈林河畔的高架橋下
- And when did it close? - 1910.
- 什麼時候關閉的? - 1910年
Okay, what about Houston... Yeah.
那豪斯頓
- Houston and Greenwich. When is that? - 1898.
- 豪斯頓和格林威治是何時? - 1898年
And the Hudson and 155th was closed in 1906.
哈德遜及155街交口的 那一家是在1906年關閉的
1906, 1898...
1906 1898…
All right, let's... 1898.
好 我們去
Houston and Greenwich. You call emergency services, Paulie.
去豪斯頓和格林威治那家 保利 你通知緊急小組
Tell them...
告訴他們…
meet us at Houston and Greenwich, okay?
到豪斯頓和格林威治 和我們會合 知道嗎?
Solomon, you get on to Hanson. He'll need about 20 guys.
索羅門 你去找韓森 叫他帶20個手下
We'll take Eddie's van.
我們開艾迪的車去
- You go with them. - Come on, guys. Let's go!
- 你和他們一塊兒去 - 我們走吧
Linc, are you there?
林肯 你在嗎?
- Yeah, ready. - We're here.
- 我準備好了 - 我們到了
Okay. Amelia?
好 愛美莉雅?
- Yeah. - Same drill. I want you in first.
- 我在 - 這次我也要你先進去
Let's do it.
動手吧
Watch yourself, Amelia.
小心點 愛美莉雅
Oh, man, I don't like this.
我不喜歡這樣
I don't like this.
Hey, Linc, I got a bad feeling about this, man.
林肯 我有不祥的預感
I think all three of us ought to get in there together.
我覺得這次 我們該三個一塊兒進去
Not yet, Paulie. Just hold back.
現在還不行 保利 等一會兒
Going down some stairs.
我現在正在下樓
Cement walls.
水泥牆
Wood crates...
很多木箱子…
large columns.
大柱子
Smells like manure down here.
這裡有堆肥的味道
Ortiz sure knows his shit.
奧迪茲真內行
Always has.
他一向如此
Metal hooks...
鐵鉤…
and a pen.
和一座圍欄
It's a slaughterhouse.
這裡是屠宰場
- E.S.U. Are here. - Hold them off.
- 緊急小組來了 - 叫他們先按兵不動
Don't let them in there and contaminate the scene.
別讓他們進去把現場弄亂
All right, hold it. Hold up. Hold up!
先別進去…
- You're not to go in. - Why?
- 你們還不可以進去 - 為什麼?
- Rhyme's orders. - Fuck him. Get me Cheney on the line.
- 這是萊姆的命令 - 去他的 幫我接錢尼
Crime scene C.O. On air.
指揮官線上上
Switch to channel 22 for E.S.U.
緊急小組在22頻道
Fuck Rhyme.
去他的萊姆
Maybe this one's still alive.
也許這個還沒死
Perp didn't leave a deadline.
兇手沒有留下時限
What does that mean?
這表示什麼?
It means we're probably too late.
這表示我們也許來的太遲
You don't know that, Rhyme.
你不能確定這點 萊姆
Get off the line.
別占線
Let's move on, Amelia.
我們進去吧 愛美莉雅
You know, there's five basic contaminants to every crime scene.
最容易污染現場的因素 共有五個
I'll skip to the worst one.
我直接說最嚴重的那個
Other cops.
其他的員警
I think I hear something.
我好像聽到聲音了
I hate this shit.
真討厭
I see something. Something's there.
我看到東西了 那裡有東西
I think I found him.
我好像找到他了
I can't... I can't tell if he's alive.
我沒辦法… 我沒辦法看出他是生是死
Oh, Jesus. He's covered in rats.
天啊 他全身都是老鼠
They're all over him.
全身都是老鼠
- We're going in. - No, you're not!
- 我們要進去了 - 不行!
Go, go!
快上!
Central, we have shots fired. Shots fired.
總局 有人開火 有人開火
Oh, God.
天啊
You were right. We never had a shot.
你說的對 我們一點勝算都沒有
He cut him up pretty bad and left him for the rats.
他把被害人割的片體鱗傷 丟在那裡喂老鼠
There's also a big cut in his leg, it's right down to the bone.
他的腿上也有一道很深的傷口
The blood attracted the rats.
血腥味引來老鼠
Goddamn son of a bitch.
真是個該死的渾蛋
You okay?
你還好吧?
I'm fine.
我很好
Wanna step aside so I can walk the grid?
你們讓開 讓我做事
Yeah.
好
Yeah, all right, let's back 'em up. Let's give her some room. Come on.
各位退後 讓她做事
Rhyme, I'm gonna walk the grid.
萊姆 我要開始工作了
Okay.
好
You know what to do.
你知道該怎麼做
I found it.
我找到了
Another cluster.
他又留下一團東西
It's a piece of old paper, just like the other two.
又是一張陳年舊紙 和另外兩張一樣
And a matchbox.
和一個火柴盒
Somebody get that black suitcase and bring it over here, please.
拜託把黑色手提箱拿來
Pull out the brown envelope.
把褐色的信封拿來
Sounds like you're starting to enjoy this work.
你越來越高明了
Damn. The press is here.
該死 記者來了
Right there.
停那裡
Lincoln Rhyme is no longer working this case. I'm taking over. Understood?
林肯萊姆已不負責此案 我從這裡接手 懂嗎?
You can do what you want, Captain, but you ought to check with Murphy first.
隨你便 隊長 不過你得先問莫菲局長
Fuck Murphy, and fuck Rhyme.
去他的莫菲局長 去他的萊姆
This has been cleared downtown. We got a dead kid in there on our hands.
總局已經授權讓我接手這案子 裡面死了個大學生
And I for one am not taking the heat for that, you understand?
我才不要背黑鍋呢 明白嗎?
Call Ortiz. Tell him and his crew to vacate Rhyme's place now, tonight.
快找奧迪茲 叫他和他的手下離開萊姆家
Excuse me, but the victim was already dead when we arrived.
我們抵達現場時 被害人已經死了
And you... half-assed patrolman working a crime scene...
他居然找你這個 三腳貓來勘查現場
those days are over.
好日子過完了
I'll take that evidence bag now, thank you.
請把證據交給我 謝謝
You can take it with a chain of custody voucher, sir.
長官 你有證據轉交授權書嗎
Are you out of your mind?
你瘋了嗎?
Let's go. You're coming with us.
我們走吧 你跟我們一塊兒來
What, are you arresting me?
你要逮捕我嗎?
You just get in the car, and keep your mouth shut to the press.
你給我上車 見到記者別亂開口
You're not gonna find any prints. The guy's too good for that.
你們找不到任何指紋的 兇手太高明了
Well, it looks like we have a nice clean friction print here.
看來我們找到一枚 很清晰的部份指紋
Unless, of course, it's yours.
該不會是你的吧
No, I was wearing gloves when I collected it.
不可能 我有戴手套
We'll know soon enough.
我們很快的便知分曉
Put this through, highest priority.
將此列為優先處理事項
- You got it. - Thank you.
- 沒問題 - 謝謝
You know, I got a feeling this perp's been in business for a long time.
我總覺得兇手殺人行之有年
"分析結果-土壞" 我同意 但現在是錢尼的問題了
That's what scares me. Do me a favor, will you?
這正是我擔心的事 幫我個忙
Check if there's been any homicides in the last 12 months...
幫我查查過去12個月是否有
involving surgically-removed flesh exposing bone.
和切被害人屍體有關的謀殺案
No problem. I'll see you soon.
沒問題 再聯絡
- Hope so, Eddie. - Hey, Thelma...
- 希望如此 艾迪 - 瑟瑪…
don't you let him run no circles around you now.
別讓他耍你
Stay right, Eddie.
保重 艾迪
"魯賓、骨頭、木塊 毛髮、蒸汽管"
Oh, that print... we just got a positive I.D. On it.
那枚指紋我們已經查證過了
Guy has three extremely violent priors.
指紋的主人 有三次暴力犯罪前科
Oh, look at that. Taxi license, no less.
你看 他還有計程車執照呢
We got him.
我們逮到他了
Way to go, boys. Somebody call the E.S.U.
幹的好 快去通知緊急小組
"證物"
Now slide out...
慢慢的…
nice and easy.
滑出來
That explains your print, Captain.
隊長 難怪你會取到指紋
He's now the fourth victim of a killing spree that has prompted NYPD brass...
目前已有四名死者 此案迫得紐約警局高層…
to launch a special task force to track the killer.
為了追查兇手 組成特別小組
This morning's raid in Queens follows leads found at an earlier murder site.
今天早上警方突擊皇后區 發現該處稍早也發生謀殺案
Detectives at the scene...
現場的警探…
I was hoping you'd show up.
我正希望你會來呢
- He's been worried about you. - Yeah, sure.
- 他很擔心你 - 是啊
Viewers will know Rhyme from his book, Scene of the Crime...
觀眾對林肯萊姆應該不陌生 他是犯罪現場…
a chronicle of old New York's most grisly murders...
紐約過去 最殘酷的十大罪案的作者
that topped the best-seller list earlier this year.
今年稍早這本書 躍登暢銷排行榜榜首
Didrt expect to see you again.
沒想到還會再見到你
Poor Cheney, huh?
錢尼真倒楣
Grabbed the ball with both hands, scored one for the other team.
這下子做繭自縛 長他人威風
- I can't really comment at this time. - Yeah.
- 我目前無可奉告 - 是啊
Well, I tried to warn him that the perp was too smart to leave a print.
我試著警告他 兇手太高明不會留下指紋
How you doing with that stuff?
你的進展如何?
Not too good.
不太好
Two pieces of the puzzle but I don't know what it means.
這是拼圖中的兩片 但我不瞭解其中含意
Maybe this'll help.
也許這會有幫助吧
Cheney will have your badge for that.
錢尼會撤你職的
He wouldn't give me a chain of custody voucher, so what could I do?
他沒有給我收據 我還能怎麼辦?
You could bring it back to him.
你可以拿去還給他
The man is a living monument to ineptitude.
他簡直是個大傻瓜
True. Let's take a look.
這倒沒錯 來看看吧
What do you got there?
那是什麼?
Third piece of the puzzle.
第三片拼圖
There's something really strange about it though, so you gotta smell it.
不過這片有點奇怪 你該聞一聞
Sure.
好啊
- Are you... - Oh, shit.
- 你… - 該死
Sorry.
對不起
Oh, it's okay. Take your time.
不要緊 慢慢來
You have to put it closer to my nose.
你要拿的靠我的鼻子近一些
What do you think it is?
你說這是什麼?
Kerosene?
煤油?
Possibly.
有可能
Okay, this just came in from Eddie Ortiz.
這是艾迪送來的
Amelia, could you load these into the viewer for me, please?
愛美莉雅 能不能幫我把這些 放進掃瞄器?
Sorry about that, Thelma.
抱歉啦 瑟瑪
E.C.U., view scan.
啟動掃瞄器
"Dear Linc, I'm enclosing photos of four unsolved homicides...
"親愛的林肯 我附上過去12個月內…
which took place in the last 12 months.
未偵破的四件罪案
Flesh has been surgically removed from each of the victims' extremities.
每一名被害人四肢 都被兇手熟練的切去肌肉
I miss you. Love, Eddie.'
我很想你 艾迪"
I'm gonna spare myself the pleasure, if you don't mind.
我先告退 希望兩位不會介意
Okay, Thelma.
不要緊 瑟瑪
Zoom.
放大
Same mark.
相同的標記
Right.
右邊
Zoom. Zoom.
放大…
Same messages.
相同的訊息
It's him.
就是他
The perp was trying to make contact even then.
兇手當時就想和我們聯絡了
But Cheney never put it together.
但是錢尼卻沒看出其中關連
Dysreflexia seizure, a bad one.
這次抽筋很嚴重
Hang on, hang on. Breathe, Rhyme.
忍著點 呼吸 萊姆
Come on. Breathe with me. Breathe!
快呼吸…
The damn catheter's blocked.
該死的導管堵住了
Just let me get a B.P. On you. Stay with me.
我幫你量血壓 忍著點
Stay with me. Breathe!
快點呼吸
Hang on, now. Hang on. Just let me check you.
忍著點 讓我幫你做檢查
Diastolic's over 125. I gotta get it down now.
舒張壓超過125 我一定要降壓
Just give it a few seconds to work. Come on, breathe with me.
幾秒鐘後就見效了 快點呼吸
Breathe with me, Rhyme. Rhyme!
快呼吸 萊姆…
Come on, now.
加油
Hang on, Rhyme. Hang on, man.
忍著點 萊姆 加油
Is he gonna make it?
他撐得過去嗎?
If he does, he won't be happy.
他如果撐得過去一定會很生氣
What are you talking about?
你在說什麼?
He's already finalized arrangements to self -terminate.
他已經決定要安樂死
He's got a doctor friend to help with his " final transition,' as he calls it.
他說服了他的醫生朋友 幫他進行安樂死
But suicide? I mean...
自殺?我是說…
It's the seizures.
就是這種抽筋發作
Any one of them could put him into a vegetative state.
他隨時可能因此變成植物人
That's what he fears more than anything.
這是他最害怕的事
- Who is it? - Captain Cheney.
- 哪一位? - 我是錢尼隊長
What can I help you with?
請問有什麼事嗎?
Police business. Open up, please.
這是員警公務 請開門
Mr. Rhyme is asleep.
萊姆先生睡了
Well, wake him up. I need to see him now.
叫他起來 我要和他談談
Let me deal with this asshole Cheney. You watch him.
我去對付錢尼 你來看著他
Anything, just call me. He's all right.
有事就叫我 他會好起來的
Look, lady.
聽著 小姐
Now, I hope you know that obstructing justice is a felony offense.
你知道妨礙公務是重罪吧?
Look, don't " lady' me, and I know my rights.
少來這套 我知道我的權利
Now, unless you have a warrant, you can't come in here.
你沒有逮捕令就不准進來
Oh, I'm coming in...
才怪…
'cause I have reason to believe there's stolen evidence in there.
因為我有理由相信 他身邊有偷來的證物
What's your full name?
你的全名是什麼?
Thelma what?
你姓什麼?
Well, what did you say your name was?
你說你叫什麼名字?
"給林肯萊姆警探 紐約警局上"
You got a smart mouth, and it's gonna get you in trouble one day.
你真是牙尖嘴利 總有一天會惹禍上身
And it may bite your ass if you don't stop trying to aggravate my patient.
如果你持續騷擾我的病人 我會讓你好看
I'm gonna leave now, but I'll be back.
我走就是了 但我會回來
And when I come back, it'll be with a warrant.
我回來的時候會帶著逮捕令
And I looked everywhere, and I thought the conductor was gonna be so angry.
我到處都找了 我以為指揮會很生氣
And I kept on searching everywhere.
我一直到處找
And finally, it was right on my lap.
結果發現居然就在我的腿上
Grandma can't wait to see you.
你外婆等不及要見你了
- What'd I do? - First off...
我做了什麼?
you're carrying a fare, and your meter's not on.
第一 你車上載了乘客 卻沒有跳表
And number two, your hack license is not properly displayed...
第二 你的計程車執照 沒有擺好
There's laws against molesting the handicapped, you know.
對殘障者性騷擾是犯法的
Yeah?
是嗎?
I wasrt a pretty sight, was I?
很可怕 對不對?
Thelma told me about your plans for your " final transition.'
瑟瑪告訴我 你打算要安樂死
Cop to cop, that subject's not open to discussion.
我不想談這件事
Why... would you miss me?
為什麼…你會想我嗎?
Well, destiny's what we make it, right?
命運是靠我們自己開創 不是嗎?
Touche.
真是一針見血
Now, you seem to have your reasons for checking out.
也許你不想活 有你的理由 我只是…
I would have expected more from someone like you.
我沒想到你這樣的人 會做出這種決定
Well, I might surprise you and...
我也許會讓你大出意外…
live forever.
來個長生不死
Nothing you could do would surprise me, Rhyme.
你做的任何事 都不會讓我感到意外
Well, look who's still in the land of the living.
看看是誰重回人間了
For the moment.
這只是暫時而已
Cheney was here, huffing and puffing.
錢尼來這裡叫囂了一翻
Promised to return with a warrant.
他說下一次要帶著逮捕令來
Sorry I missed him.
可惜我錯過了
If that's him, tell him I'm...
如果是他就說我在…
- Say no more. - Skiing.
- 別說了 - 滑雪
Hello?
喂?
Oh, hey, Paulie. Hang on.
嗨 保利 稍等
Linc, I don't know if this is anything more than a coincidence...
林肯 我不知道 這是不是純屬巧合
but a taxi inspector was killed today by a cabbie who was off the meter.
不過今天一位交警臨檢 計程車司機不跳表時被殺了
Thing about this taxi... a witness, a male...
我們有一名男性目擊證人
wouldn't give his name...
他不願透露自己的姓名
saw the taxi speeding away with an old man and a little girl inside.
指稱計程車逃逸時車上 還載著一個老人和一個女孩
Probably the doer that called.
說不定證人就是兇手
Jesus, he's got a kid.
天啊 他抓了個孩子
And an old man.
和一個老人
- Thank you, Paulie. - Okay.
- 謝謝你 保利 - 別客氣
We better take a closer look at that third piece of the puzzle.
我們來看看第三片拼圖吧
Close.
放大
Three murders, three evidence clusters...
三件謀殺案 三件證物…
three pieces of paper.
三張紙
View scan.
啟動掃瞄器
Come on, Thelma. You're the queen of puzzles. What do you see?
瑟瑪 你是拼圖高手 有沒有看出什麼端倪來?
I'm looking.
我在看
What if we lower the little one?
把小片的移下來如何?
That one.
那一片
Now twist that big one around.
把大片的轉過來
Now, doesn't that kinda look like a face?
這看起來不是有點像 一張臉嗎?
Mouth, nose, eye.
嘴巴 鼻子 眼睛
Enance.
放大
Fade.
淡出
That's a womars face.
是一個女人的臉孔
Yes, it is.
沒錯
It's a logo.
這是一個商標
And old, turn-of-the-century...
是本世紀初…
publisher's logo.
出版商的商標
You know it?
你怎麼知道?
I used to own a few of the books...
我以前也有過幾本他們的書
gothic stories...
都是哥德式小說…
crime stories.
犯罪小說
The killer is pointing us to an old book.
兇手要我們去找一本舊書
Can I help you?
有什麼事嗎?
I called before about turn-of-the-century crime books.
我剛剛打過電話來 要找本世紀初的犯罪小說
Around the corner. Help yourself.
就在轉角 你自己去找吧
Thanks.
謝謝
"人骨拼圖: 謀殺犯的自白"
Aviation two to central. We're taking a fly-by at the Brooklyn Bridge.
飛行員呼叫中心 我們正經過布魯克林橋
Report appears unfounded at this time.
顯然該報導是空穴來風
Will proceed to check East River shoreline and advise.
我們會到河東岸繼續搜查 請指示
I need more small boats over here to search under the pier.
多派一些小船到碼頭下去搜
By the heliport, under the pier.
到直升機起降場及碼頭下去找
Lincoln, it was the last murder in the book.
林肯 那是書上 最後一件謀殺案
They've got to be along the shore here somewhere.
他們一定就在岸邊的某處
Listen, the lab says the odor we smelled...
聽我說 實驗室證實 我們在第三片拼圖上…
on the third piece of the puzzle is probably diesel fuel
聞到的味道也許是柴油
Now, there's an old boat refueling station...
在史丹唐渡船碼頭
at the Staten Island Ferry pier.
有一個廢棄的船隻加油站
Check the pilings under the pier.
你到那個碼頭去找找
Found them!
找到了!
Over here! Here!
在這裡!
Central, I can see someone with a light...
中心 我看到下方 有人拿著手電筒
signaling us from the old Staten Island Ferry pier.
在史丹唐渡船碼頭 對我們做信號
There appears to be two bodies in the water next to the pilings.
碼頭的柱子下 似乎有兩具人體
Be advised subject signaling is most likely NYPD officer at the site.
各位請注意 做信號的人 很有可能是紐約市員警
Over here! Here!
在這裡!
Under the pilings!
在柱子下!
Come over to the ladder.
到梯子這邊來
Central, be advised aideds are out of the water...
中心 他們已經被 救出水面
and E.M.S. Is working on them at this time.
緊急小組正在 對他們施行急救
- On standby. - Clear the airway.
- 待命 - 做人工呼吸
Rhyme, are you there?
萊姆 你還在嗎?
Yeah.
對
It looks like we're too late.
看來我們遲了一步
Naw, forget it. He's dead.
算了 他死了
Bring the chopper in.
叫直升機過來
The old man is gone.
老人已經死了
They're still working on the girl, but it doesn't look good.
他們還在救那個女孩 但看來不樂觀
We need a level one task force mobilization now!
趕快派急救小組來!
- Try again. I know she's still there. - Come on, kid.
- 再試試 我知道她還沒死 - 加油 孩子
Come on, try.
加油
You can do it. Come on.
你可以的 加油
Breathe.
呼吸
- There you go! - She's breathing.
- 就是這樣! - 她開始呼吸了
I think she's gonna be okay. She's breathing, Lincoln. Can you hear me?
我想她不會有事的 她在呼吸 林肯 你聽得到嗎?
- I think she's gonna make it. - Yeah. Good.
- 她應該沒事了 - 很好
We got her by the clues that he left for us.
我們要去找 他為我們留下來的證據
See what you can find around the fuel tanks.
你到油箱旁邊找找
All right.
好
Lincoln, I found it.
林肯 我找到了
It's a map of some kind, some chunk of a clean bone...
好像是一張地圖和一塊骨頭
and a piece of a medal or a badge or something.
和一個金屬片 看來像是徽章
There's some initials engraved. Looks like...
金屬片上有刻字 看起來像…
a"P' and a" B,' or a...
一個P和一個B
It's a " D.' It's definitely a " D.'
是D 絕對是D
P. D... sounds like a cop's badge.
PD…好像是警徽
You think he's gonna kill a cop?
你認為他打算殺員警?
Could be.
可能吧
- Thelma? - Maps?
- 瑟瑪? - 你要地圖嗎?
Tell me about the map.
描述一下那張地圖
Looks like an old subway map.
看起來好像是舊的地鐵圖
I don't recognize any of the stations.
但站名都很陌生
You know, when I was scanning those asbestos sites...
當我在調查石棉工廠時
I came across a lot of stations that aren't in use anymore.
我找到了很多 現在已經廢棄的地鐵站
Okay. There it is... the oldest station.
好 這是最老的地鐵站
On your map, is there an old station indicated at the tip of Manattan?
地圖上在曼哈頓角 是不是有一個地鐵站?
Navy Street.
海軍街站
- It's right next to the pier. - Shit.
- 那站就在碼頭旁 - 該死的
Cheney's here.
錢尼來了
You talking to Rhyme on that thing? Give me the radio.
你在和萊姆通話? 把無線電給我
Listen, Linc. This is Cheney, man. What the hell do you think you're doing?
聽著 林肯 我是錢尼 你在搞什麼鬼?
Stealing evidence is a goddamn felony. You know that.
偷取證物是重罪 你應該明白
To my understanding, there's no chain of evidence voucher.
我相信 你並沒有證據轉交授權書
Oh, yeah? Well, I got some news for you.
是嗎?我有事要告訴你
You are not a cop anymore. You understand that?
你再也不是員警了 懂了沒?
What you are is a fucking meddling cripple.
你不過是個 干涉我們辦案的廢人
Now, I'm gonna place your little gofer here under arrest.
我現在要逮捕你的小女朋友
You don't mind that, do ya?
你不會介意吧 對不對?
Lock her up.
把她押下去
Where'd she go?
她到哪裡去了?
"海軍街地下鐵南街站"
I'm inside the Navy Street tunnel.
我現在已經進了海軍街遂道
There's gray dust everywhere. It's all over my shoes.
到處都是灰塵 弄得我鞋子上都是
There's footprints...
有腳印…
one set of footprints.
有一組腳印
Amelia?
愛美莉雅?
Hello, Lincoln, hello.
喂 林肯…
Amelia? Hello?
愛美莉雅?喂?
The mobile unit you've called is not responding...
您撥的的號碼 沒有回應…
or is outside the coverage area.
或是已經離開通訊範圍
Recall.
重撥
"往華許高地 160街"
No dust... He changed the numbers.
沒有灰塵… 他改了號碼
78499... what is it?
78499…什麼意思?
What does it mean?
到底是什麼意思?
Help me, Rhyme. Help me.
快想啊…
He's gonna kill Rhyme.
他要殺了萊姆
Coming.
來了
Hey. What are you doing here?
你來做什麼?
Is that Amelia?
是不是愛美莉雅來了?
Bed mode.
調整床墊
Thelma, is that you?
瑟瑪 是你嗎?
No, it's me, Richard.
不 是我 理查
Richard. What's up?
理查 什麼事?
Thelma asked me to come by, check the heart-pacing machine.
瑟瑪要我過來檢查一下 心跳節律器
"緊急床墊調節啟動"
- Where is Thelma? - Out in the hall.
- 瑟瑪呢? - 在外面
"備用電力-危險"
Phone mode.
電話模式
I thought it was time we had a little quiet moment together, you and I.
我想我們現在應該 好好獨處一下
- No interruptions. - Okay.
- 不要外人來干擾 - 好
What's on your mind, Richard?
你在想什麼 理查?
I think it's time to set the record straight, Mr. Rhyme.
我想現在該把話說清楚了 萊姆先生
Syracuse... you remember Syracuse, don't you?
西那庫斯… 你記得西那庫斯吧?
You wrote an expert opinion.
你發表了你的專家意見
I've written thousands of opinions, Richard.
我發表的意見不計其數 理查
Don't fucking tell me you don't remember Syracuse.
別告訴我你不記得西那庫斯
They called it an investigation. It was a witch hunt.
他們美其名那是調查 其實根本是誣陷
There was a forensics cop up in Syracuse, New York.
紐約西那庫斯 有一名負責現場勘驗的員警
Marcus Andrews.
馬可斯安德魯
Okay, yeah. That was the cop that was...
我想起來了 他們懷疑那名警探…
suspected of tampering with evidence in some homicide cases, right?
擅改謀殺案中的 現場證物 對不對?
Nothing was tampered with.
那根本是一派胡言
Six innocent people went to jail, One hung himself.
六名無辜的人因此下獄 其中一人甚至上吊自殺
No, no. No.They went to jail because they were guilty. They were scum.
不 他們坐牢是因為他們有罪 他們是人渣
- But he doctored the serology reports. - No. Nothing was doctored.
- 他偽造了血液學檢查報告 - 不 他什麼都沒有偽造
He planted blood evidence at the crime scenes.
他在現場佈置了血液證據
My work was impeccable.
我的工作無懈可擊
Where we going with this...
你到底想幹什麼…
Marcus?
馬可斯?
Your report destroyed my life.
你的報告毀了我的一生
You know my report was not a legal finding.
你應該知道我的報告 並不等於調查結果
You never gave me the opportunity to defend myself.
你沒有給我機會 讓我自我辯護
- I never even met you. - I was sent to prison for six years.
- 我根本沒見過你 - 我為此坐了六年牢
I spent two more years trying to get to you.
之後又花了兩年想報復你
Do you know what happens to a cop in jail Do you?
你知道員警坐牢 會有什麼下場嗎?
Every day... every single day...
每一天 日復一日…
over and over, I was brutalized.
我都受到其他犯人的淩虐
I became a human toilet...
我簡直是生不如死
because of your expert opinion.
一切都是因為你的報告
Well, you will never point the finger of blame at anyone ever again.
我再也不讓你指責任何人了
You were never as good as they said you were, Mr. Rhyme.
萊姆先生 你根本沒有傳說中的那麼出色
I played you. I tested you.
你被我耍得團團轉 我考驗你
I gave you every clue.
我留了許多線索給你
You and your little helper couldn't save those people.
你和你的小跟班幫不了那些人
Their blood is on your hands. You failed.
你雙手沾滿了他們的鮮血 你失敗了
You failed, you fuck.
你失敗了 你這個王八蛋
Game of chess, Mr. Rhyme. Some people win, some people lose.
就像下棋一樣 有人輸 有人贏
I win, Mr. Rhyme. I win, you lose.
我贏了 萊姆先生 我贏 你輸
What kind of vegetable would you like to be, Mr. Rhyme?
你想變成什麼樣的植物人 萊姆先生?
A carrot?
胡蘿蔔?
How 'bout a zucchini?
胡瓜如何?
Zucchini? You wanna be a zucchini?
胡瓜? 你想當胡瓜嗎?
I'm sorry. I didn't hear you.
很抱歉 我沒聽到你說什麼
Did you say zucchini?
你說胡瓜嗎?
You wanna play?
你想玩?
Shall we cut out your tongue, Mr. Rhyme?
要不要我割掉你的舌頭 萊姆先生?
How 'bout your eye? Your eye...
要不要挖出你的眼睛? 你的眼睛…
we'll just pop it right out of there.
我把你的眼睛挖出來如何?
No. Let's leave that for now.
不 我看還是先別急吧
You can watch me. You can watch me while I gut you open...
我要你眼睜睜的看我…
right down the middle.
把你開腸剖肚
What?
什麼?
What? What?
什麼?…
Can you hear me? Lincoln.
你聽得到我嗎 林肯?
Oh, God.
天啊
Step aside now.
讓開
I've always loved this view.
我一向喜歡這裡的視野
Ilike it too, Doc.
我也是 醫生
It's looking better every day.
這城市真的是越來越美了
- Hey, how you guys doing? - Santa!
- 你們好嗎? - 聖誕老公公!
- Good. - Hi!
- 好極了 - 嗨!
Ho, ho, ho, ho!
哈 哈 哈!
Hey, Linc. You got an operating license for that?
林肯 你有使用輪椅的 執照嗎?
I got a learner's permit.
我有學習駕照
- How's your boyfriend, Morris? - Oh, he's in florida.
- 你的男朋友莫利斯好嗎? - 他在佛羅里達
- He play golf. He's okay. - Playing golf!
- 他去打高爾夫球 他好得很 - 打高爾夫球!
- Captain flash on wheels. - Yo, Paulie. Merry Christmas.
- 真是輪椅神探 - 保利 聖誕快樂
Merry Christmas.
聖誕快樂
Hey, Linc, if you're gonna be cruisir you might as well be amusir
林肯 這玩意兒 給你掛在輪椅上
- There you go. - Thank you, Eddie.
- 拿去吧 - 謝謝你 艾迪
It's nice.
真好看
- Come on in. - Merry Christmas.
- 請進 - 聖誕快樂
Merry Christmas.
聖誕快樂
You're looking real good, Mr. Rhyme.
萊姆先生 你的氣色真好
Mr. Rhyme?
萊姆先生?
It's Lincoln to you. Loosen your shorts.
叫我林肯 別這麼拘束
Oh, my goodness.
天啊
Oh, my goodness. Merry Christmas. What are you doing here?
我的天啊 聖誕快樂 你來幹嘛?
- Merry Christmas, Uncle Lincoln. - Oh, give me a kiss!
- 聖誕快樂 林肯舅舅 - 過來親一個
Merry Christmas, Kimmy. How are you?
聖誕快樂 金咪 你好嗎?
How you doing, Tony? I didn't know you were gonna make this trip.
你好嗎 東尼? 我不知道你們會來
Wouldrt be a surprise if you knew.
你知道就不叫驚喜了
Oh, I'm sorry. Amelia, this is my sister, Janine, her family.
對不起 愛美莉雅 這是我妹妹珍妮一家
- Amelia. - Yeah, I know. Hi.
- 這是愛美莉雅 - 我知道 嗨
- You know? - We've met.
- 你知道? - 我們早就認識了
On the phone. How you doing?
我們通過電話 你好嗎?
Merry Christmas, Lincoln.
聖誕快樂 林肯
Merry Christmas.
聖誕快樂!